<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Service Mesh on Keep calm and Write something</title><link>https://cychong47.github.io/tags/service-mesh/</link><description>Recent content in Service Mesh on Keep calm and Write something</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 02:38:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cychong47.github.io/tags/service-mesh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>NGNIX for service mesh</title><link>https://cychong47.github.io/post/2017/ngnix-for-service-mesh/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 14:39:11 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://cychong47.github.io/post/2017/ngnix-for-service-mesh/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.infoq.com/news/2017/09/nginx-platform-service-mesh?utm_source=facebook&amp;amp;utm_medium=link&amp;amp;utm_campaign=calendar"&gt;NGINX Releases Microservices Platform, OpenShift Ingress Controller, and Service Mesh Preview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NGNIX also join for service mesh bandwagon?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="ngnix-application-platform"&gt;NGNIX Application Platform&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NGINX Plus, the commercial variant of the popular open source NGINX web server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NGINX Web Application Firewall (WAF)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NGINX Unit, a new open source application server that can run PHP, Python and Go&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NGINX Controller, a centralised control plane for monitoring and management of NGINX Plus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="additional-release"&gt;Additional release&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a Kubernetes Ingress Controller solution for load balancing on the Red Hat OpenShift Container Platform&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an implementation of NGINX as a service proxy for the Istio service mesh control plane.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NGINX has also released nginmesh, an open source preview version of NGINX as a service proxy for Layer 7 load balancing and proxying within the Istio service mesh platform. It aims to provide key capabilities and integration with Istio when deployed as a sidecar container, and will facilitate communication between services in a &amp;ldquo;standard, reliable, and secure manner&amp;rdquo;. Additionally, NGINX will collaborate as part of the Istio community by joining the Istio networking special interest group.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>