<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Inspiration on Keep calm and Write something</title><link>https://cychong47.github.io/tags/inspiration/</link><description>Recent content in Inspiration on Keep calm and Write something</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 02:38:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cychong47.github.io/tags/inspiration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>19 hard things you need to do to be successful</title><link>https://cychong47.github.io/post/2015/19-hard-things-you-need-to-do-to-be-successful/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 14:58:06 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://cychong47.github.io/post/2015/19-hard-things-you-need-to-do-to-be-successful/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Last login: Thu Dec 10 00:38:48 on ttys000
Chae-yongs-MacBook-Pro:~ cychong$
Chae-yongs-MacBook-Pro:~ cychong$ vi hard.txt
Chae-yongs-MacBook-Pro:~ cychong$ ack &amp;ldquo;You have to&amp;rdquo; hard.txt | sort | uniq &amp;gt; a
Chae-yongs-MacBook-Pro:~ cychong$ vi a
Chae-yongs-MacBook-Pro:~ cychong$ ack &amp;ldquo;You have to&amp;rdquo; hard.txt | uniq &amp;gt; a
Chae-yongs-MacBook-Pro:~ cychong$ vi a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to do the hard things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to make the call you’re afraid to make.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to get up earlier than you want to get up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to give more than you get in return right away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to care more about others than they care about you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to fight when you are already injured, bloody, and sore.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to feel unsure and insecure when playing it safe seems smarter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to lead when no one else is following you yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to invest in yourself even though no one else is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to look like a fool while you’re looking for answers you don’t have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to grind out the details when it’s easier to shrug them off.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to deliver results when making excuses is an option.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to search for your own explanations even when you’re told to accept the “facts.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to make mistakes and look like an idiot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to try and fail and try again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to run faster even though you’re out of breath.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to be kind to people who have been cruel to you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to meet deadlines that are unreasonable and deliver results that are unparalleled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to be accountable for your actions even when things go wrong.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to keep moving towards where you want to be no matter what’s in front of you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;출처 : &lt;a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/hard-things-you-need-to-do-to-be-successful-2015-12?amp"&gt;http://www.businessinsider.com/hard-things-you-need-to-do-to-be-successful-2015-12?amp&lt;/a&gt;
20 substitutions on 20 lines&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>